Guide to the Turkish Photography Collection 1910-1990 AD.MC.007
AbuDhabi
- 636 Scénes et Types - Le Couscous - Two females in traditional dress, preparing couscous with a green postage stamp on the front. French writing on the back in pencil., 12 January 1918 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Postcard of a large white building with a Luna Park sign on the front and men in military uniform walking on a dirt road. English writing on the back in pencil. Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt., undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Donkeys; English Writing; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Men; Postcards
- No 219 Alger - Femme et coiffure oranaise - A female in traditional dress with an ornate cone shaped hat. French writing on the back in black ink with a blue postage stamp., undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Algiers, Algeria; French Writing; Postal Stamps; Postcards; Traditional Dress; Women
- 1060 Scénes et Types - Fileuse indigene - A female in traditional dress with two small childern with tents and date palms in the background. Algiers, Algeria. French writing on the back in black ink., 25 December 1911 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Bedouin; Children; French Writing; Postcards; Traditional Dress
- Jeunes Arabes - Two small children in tradtional dress drinking out of an ornate water jug., undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Children; Drinking; French Writing; Traditional Dress
- No 12 - Algérie - Mauraesque à la fountaine - A Moorish woman filling up a small pot with water from a fountain. French writing on the back wiht a blue postage stamp., 25 June 1904 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Algiers, Algeria; Fountains; French Writing; Postal Stamps; Postcards; The Moors; Traditional Dress; Women
- 402 T - Jeune Mauresque - Postcard of a young Moorish female in traditional dress standing in front of a wall. French writing on the front and back in black ink., 18 May 1915 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  French Writing; Postcards; The Moors; Women
- 1506 Luxor Temple Statue of Rameses II - A male standing in front of a Stautue of Rameses II. Writing in English in black ink., 21 December [...] (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Archaeological Sites; English Writing; Luxor, Egypt; Postal Stamps; Postcards; Temples; United States of America
- 54 Jeune Kayble - A young child in traditional dress carrying a water jug on their head. French writing on the back in black ink., 30 August 1917 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Children; French Writing; Postal Stamps; Postcards; Traditional Dress
- Constantinople - Sept Tours - Castle turets and walls with old wooden houses in front of the walls. French writing on the back in black ink with a purple postage stamp., undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Archaeological Sites; Castles; Constantinople; French Writing; Istanbul, Turkey; Postal Stamps; Postcards
- Bosphore - Châteaux d'Asie et College Robert à Roumeli Hissar - Rumelihisari Fortress and the Robert College of Istanbul in the background., undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Archaeological Sites; Bosphorous; Castles; Postcards; Rumelihisari
- Istanbul - Vue de Scutari au Bosphore - Scutari (Üsküdar) and the Bosphorous in Turkey. Romania writing on the back in black ink, two green and one purple postage stamp., undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Boats; Bosphorous; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Postal Stamps; Postcards; Romanian Writing; Uskudar, Turkey
- 6446 Scenes et Types - Femmes Mauraesque en Promenade - veiled Moorish women walking in the street., 1 Septembre (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Children; French Writing; Postal Stamps; Postcards; The Moors; Traditional Dress; Walking; Women
- Constantinople - Le Cimetiére d'Eyoub et la Corne d'Or - Postcard of the Eyüp Cemetery and the Golden Horn. Dutch writing on the back in black ink., 19 October 1912 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Bosphorous; Cemetery; Dutch Writing; Eyup, Istanbul, Turkey; Postal Stamps; Postcards; The Golden Horn
- 6146 Jeunes Filles cherchant de l'eau dans l'Oued - Young females searching for water with camels and date palm in the background. Algiers, Algeria. French writing on the back in blue ink., 20 March 1919 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Camels; Children; Donkeys; French Writing; Girls; Postcards
- 52 Femmes Mauresque - Two Moorish females in traditional dress and jewelry reclining in a tent. Green postage stamp on the back and French writing on the back in black ink. Algeria., 28 December 1902 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  French Writing; Jewelry; Postal Stamps; Postcards; The Moors; Women
- Istanbul, Sülemaniye - Vue Mosquée Sulemanié - Postcard of the Süleymaniye Mosque with the Bosphorous in the background. Dutch writing on the back in blue ink., 53 September 1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Dutch Writing; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Postal Stamps; Postcards; Suleymaniye Mosque
- Jardin d'Acclimatation (L'Afrique Mystérieuse) - 11 Moe. 0urs du Sahara Algérien, Danses des Ouled-Naïls - Postcard of traditional dressed females doing a dance in front of a white building with decorative tiles on the wall with an orange stamp on the front. French writing on the back in black ink., undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Algeria; Dancing; French Writing; Postal Stamps; Postcards; Traditional Dress; Women
- 9 Alexandria - Cherid Pacha Street - Postcard of men in hats and suits walking along a street with stone buildings in Alexandria, Egypt. Italian writing on the back in black ink., 22 June 1929 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Alexandria, Egypt; Buildings; Italian Writing; Men; Streets
- Constantinople - Intérieur de Ste-Sophie - Postcard of the interior of the Hagia Sohpia with Ottoman writing on the front in pencil and in black ink of the back., undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Constantinople; Hagia Sophia; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Ottoman Writing; Postcards
- A female with short hair and flower patterned dress in front of a painted backdrop, holding onto a water vessel on a lion pedestal., 14 May 1921 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Hungarian Writing; Painted Backdrops; Postcards; Studio Photography; Women
- 50 Istanbul Aya Sofya ici - The Hagia Sophia. French writing on the back in pencil., 11 September 1952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  French Writing; Hagia Sophia; Istanbul, Turkey; Postal Stamps; Postcards
- An older female in a black dress with light spots holding a cigarette in her left hand. Görcek Beyoglu, Istanbul. Same female from AD-MC-007_ref361, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Studio Photography; Women
- A group of young females in school unifrom black dresses with white shirts, one is holding a glass bottle and two balloons., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Drinking; Girls; Photographic Prints; Schools; Uniforms
- A group of males and one females with two shisha/nargile pipes seated at outdoor tables., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Drinking; Group Portraits; Hats; Nargile; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Tea
- Three males behind a desk in an office., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Men; Offices; Photographic Prints
- A young child in a flower patterned outfit with patterned cushions in the background., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Children; Furnishings; Photographic Prints
- Three older females in the countryside at a picnic, one is seated in a chair with a coffee cup., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Drinking; Gardens; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Women
- A family group having a picnic at the beach in front of their VW Bug., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Cars; Family; Photographic Prints
- A family portrait, two younger males in suits, one younger female in a black dress and an older female in a black dress with white details. Foto Kenan, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Family Portraits; Foto Kenan; Photographic Prints
- Three older males standing in front of some stone stairs with trees in the background., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Men; Parks; Photographic Prints
- A male in military uniform and a male in a suit standing in front of a painted backdrop with mountains on it., undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Men; Photographic Prints; Soldiers; Studio Photography
- A large family group with the bride in a veil in the middle back row., undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Family Portraits; Flowers; Photographic Prints; Wedding Portraits
- An older male with a hat, standing in a field with high plants and a child on his shoulders., undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Children; Family; Gardens; Photographic Prints
- An older male embracing two small children, female child is holding a baby., undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Birth; Children; Family; Photographic Prints
- A small female child sitting on the fence of a balcony in front of a house., undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- A young couple standing looking off camera. Foto Kanarya., undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Couple; Flowers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- An older female in a black dress and a younger male standing next to a table with a flower decoration on it., undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Family Portraits; Photographic Prints
- A young girl in a flower print dress and head scarf standing next to a covered pedestal., undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Girls; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A young couple in Western clothes standing on an Oriental carpet in front of a dark curtain. Turkish writing on the front in green ink., 9 March 1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Couple; Photographic Prints
- A young couple, male in military uniform and female in a dark suit with square patterned collar. Studio Kenan., undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Couple; Foto Kenan; Photographic Prints; Soldiers; Studio Photography
- Two females in light dresses with puffy updos. Seated female has a large black purse on her left arm. Ulus., undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- A young female with short wavy hair and a black dress with a large white flower in the cleavage., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- A family group, older female and younger female are both wearing white dresses with the same patterned bow and tie on them., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Family Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A group of five males standing on grass with trees in the background., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Gardens; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints
- A young couple, female in a black dress with a five petal flower design, male in a light suit., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Couple; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A male wearing aviator sunglasses, seated next to a marina with boats flying Turkish flags in the background., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Boats; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Flags; Men
- A young girl in a white princess outfit and a young male in a prince outfit standing in front of some curtains with stars on them., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Children; Performance Play; Photographic Prints
- Two older females seated in wooden chairs in satin dress with drinks in their hands., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- A group of males and females at the beach in their bathing suits. Writing on the back in blue ink and pencil., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Bathing Suits; Beach; Group Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Women
- A young female in a dark fur coat with a dark brooch with flowers on her left chest., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Fur Garments; Hats; Individual Portrait; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Women
- A young couple, possibily newly married, in between large flower arrangements., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Ceremony; Couple; Flowers; Photographic Prints
- A family group, a seated older male with a suit and tie on surrounded by three standing females of varying ages., undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- A group of females of varying ages seated indoors with two young children standing in front of them in white dresses., undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Children; Family; Furnishings
- A male with dark rimmed glasses in a suit with two females, one in a dark dress, one in a light dress., undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Family; Photographic Prints
- Six siblings of varying ages, the youngest is seated on a flower patterend cushion. Foto Refik, Balikesir, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Balikesir, Turkey; Family Portraits; Photographic Prints; Soldiers; Studio Photography
- A young couple in their bathing suits standing on some rocks at the beach, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Bathing Suits; Beach; Couple; Mountains
- A mixed group of males and females standing in a room with several large desks in it, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Men; Offices; Photographic Prints; Women
- A young female in a white dress with small flowers on it seated on a bench with her legs crossed, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- A group of young males and females in front of a building, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Women
- A male standing in a Western suit next to a light plant stand with a painted backdrop in the background., undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Furnishings; Individual Portrait; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- A family group, one older female with four young children in front of her. Young female is wearing a light flower patterned dress with a large bow on her head., undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- A young female and a young male standing on a square tiled street with buildings in the background., undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Children; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Streets
- A bride standing with a seated covered female and a standing male in a dark suit. Same couple from AD-MC-007_ref728 and AD-MC-007_ref821., undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Couple; Gardens; Photographic Prints; Wedding Portraits
- A young male and young female in their bathing suits at the beach with umbrellas in the background, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Bathing Suits; Beach; Children; Photographic Prints
- A young couple, female is wearing a dark skirt suit and holding a bouquet of flowers, male is holding female, dressed in dark Western suit. Foto Moda., undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Couple; Flowers; Foto Moda; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A young female is wearing a watch on her left arm. Studio Gorcek. Same female in AD-MC-007_ref708, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Handtinting; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Gorcek; Studio Photography; Women
- A young female in a dark dress with a light lace collar. Overpainted lips in red. Studio Gorcek., undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- A young female in a dress with two light pom-poms on it, leaning aginst a wall. Foto Sabah, Beyoglu, Istanbul., undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Children; Foto Sabah; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A couple, female in a dark dress with a light lace collar and male in a dark suit. Studio Sabah, Istanbul., undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Children; Coats; Couple; Foto Sabah; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A female in dark coat, holding a dark purse and wearing a patterned scarf on her head. Foto Moda., undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Foto Moda; Head Covers; Individual Portrait; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Women
- A young male with a toothbrush mustache, in a dark suit and fedora. Turkish writing on the front in black ink., 4 March 1934 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Hats; Individual Portrait; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- A shirtless male wearing boxing gloves, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Furnishings; Men; Photographic Prints; Sports
- An older male in a pin stripped suit with two females in dark dressed. Foto Sabah., undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Family Portraits; Foto Sabah; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A young female in a light sweater with a stitched flower pattern on the left chest., undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- A couple on their wedding day. Turkish writing on the front in black ink., 14 July 1942 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Couple; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veil
- A mixed family group standing on the steps of a building with writing on it., undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- A family group, two females in dresses with squares on them holding a young baby and a male in a suit. Kültür, Izmir, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Family Portraits; Izmir, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A male in a pin stripped vest with three young females in dresses and coats standing in front a wall with a gate., undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Children; Houses; Men; Photographic Prints
- A family group, older male wearing a military uniform holding the hand of a young male similarly dressed, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Children; Family Portraits; Photographic Prints; Soldiers; Studio Photography
- A young male in military uniform standing in front of some trees with a low stone wall in the background, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Soldiers; Trees
- A family group, two older females with a young male in the middle and two small females seated on blocks in flowery dresses. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- A young couple on their wedding day. Bride is wearing a flower laced cloak overtop of her dress., undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veil
- A group in formal dress and suits inside a house with a large chandelier, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Family Portraits; Photographic Prints; Wedding Ceremony
- A young male using an electric shaver standing next to a bunk bed, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Men; Photographic Prints
- A female holding a baby, both wearing white. Sencek., undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Children; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- A family group with a bride and groom standing in the middle of the group, outdoors., undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Family Portraits; Gardens; Photographic Prints; Wedding Portraits
- A family group, younger females are in dark dresses with light bows in their hair. Same couple from AD-MC-007_ref704 and AD-MC-007_ref821., undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Two older males and a younger male standing on the stairs of a building in front of a sign "T.C. Kartal Hükümet Tabipligi" (Office of a government doctor), undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Medicine; Men; Photographic Prints
- An older male with a beard seated on a chair holding a young baby with an older female and younger female standing next to them., undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Family Portraits; Houses; Photographic Prints; Students
- A younger female seated on the lap of an older female in a coat with a fur collar and hat on a bench., undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Children; Family; Fur Garments; Photographic Prints; Women
- A young child in a shiny double breasted outfit with legs crossed. Foto Sehir., undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Children; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A young female looking off camera in a black dress with a large white collar., undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Girls; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Students
- An older male in a dark suit wearing a fez, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Fez; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- A young girl in a dark dress with a light collar and a bow in her hair. Foto Rekor. Dated in blue ink on front., 16 February 1944 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Children; Foto Rekor, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A young male in a cap and gown with dark rimmed glasses, being kissed on the cheeck by an older woman in a polka dot dress., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Family; Photographic Prints; Students
- An older male and an older female both wearing glasses holding a young female between them with a vase of flowers in front of them., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Children; Family Portraits; Flowers; Photographic Prints; Toys
- A young male receiving a diploma on stage from another male, while a third male is holding a microphone., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Ceremony; Photographic Prints; Schools; Students; Teachers
- A group of males and one young female seated around a large table set for dinner., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Drinking; Eating; Flowers; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints
- A group of five females, four in dark dress, one in a light dress standing in front of large flower arrangements. Foto Sabah Beyoglu., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Flowers; Foto Sabah; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- A family group laughing and holding hands. Females are both in light silken flower dresses., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Family; Photographic Prints; Wedding Ceremony
- A young couple seated on a large curved wooden bench. Studio Mustafa., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Couple; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A portrait of an older woman in a dark dress with a light collar wearing drop earings. Studio Mustafa., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Portrait of a female with a paisley patterned scarf and hoop earings., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
- A family group, one young female with a large white bow in her hair and young female with an intricate flower head dress. Foto Berk, Izmir., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Children; Family Portraits; Izmir, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A couple, female has round dark framed glasses and male is wearing a dark jacket., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
- A group of six females of varying ages. Gorcek, Beyoglu., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Family Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Gorcek; Women
- A horse drawn carriage in a park with people in it., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Carriages & Coaches; Family; Istanbul, Turkey; Parks
- A young couple in western dress standing in front of a door with a large frosted glass window in it., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Three young females in matching white skirts and shirts standing in the grass with large trees behind them. Foto Moda, Erdek., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Foto Moda; Girls; Parks; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
- A male playing an accordion with a group of young males and females standing nearby, while other children look on., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Children; Dancing; Musical Instruments; Photographic Prints; Schools; Teachers
- An older female in a blonde wig standing in front of a metal fence with a body of water in the background., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Photographic Prints; Seas; Women
- Three young females in western dress standing in a large grass field. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Photographic Prints; Women
- A young male in a dark outfit holding a small black suitcase., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Children; Photographic Prints; Schools; Uniforms
- A young female nurse sitting on a bed embracing a young female in a dress., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Three older females and an older male and a young male sitting a living room on a dark couch., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Five females seated on a low wall in front of a large building., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Three older males in suits and ties, holding glasses and cigarettes, standing in front a white paneled wall., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- A young Turkish male in bell bottom pants, sitting in front of a body of water with large boats on it., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Two young males in the same suit with similar sashes and hats., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Six women in white lab coats standing on a road outside with trees and buildings in the background., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- An older couple seated on chairs next to a young male lying in bed., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Two young women in western dress leaning on a tree in front of a small stone wall., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- A couple seated on an ornate sofa with a young male making a grimacing face. Foto Sait, Beyoglu., undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
- A family group, possible bride in the middle in the back row standing in front of a large flower arrangement., undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Black and white photographic print of large group of males and one female standing in front of a single story building with an awning over the front door, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)